# introducing



#### address

7433 South Ave Middleton, WI 53562

tel 608.852.8243 email <u>bauer@sitespark.com</u> url <u>http://mattdb.com</u>

#### Profile

I'm a veteran Ruby and Rails developer with deep experience in both the technologies and practices of the Rails community. I've been working with Rails since 2005.

I am a devoted and passionate learner, constantly exploring and learning on my own in order to keep up to date in the field. I feel this serves me well in being able to adapt to new projects and environments. I regularly attend relevant conferences to continually sharpen my skills, and read voraciously on a wide variety of technical topics.

I value outstanding user experiences and have experience creating these at all levels of an app, from interface design to caching & performance tuning.

# Experience

Rails Developer: Igicom LLC

New York, NY

2008-Present

- + Responsible for technical planning and implementation for a range of client products
- Set up multi-server production environments for Rails, Sinatra, MySQL/Postgres, Redis, Memcached, NewRelic, etc.
- + Built iOS app and API for data retrieval
- Deployed applications to multi-stage and multi-server deployment infrastructures (responsible for set up and maintenance of some of these infrastructures as well)

Rails and User Interface Developer: Benchcoach

New York, NY

2008

- + Designed and implemented data-heavy user interface using Javascript and CSS
- + Determined best ways to convey large amounts of information in a clear and succinct fashion

**Developer:** Epic Systems Corporation

Madison, WI

2005-2008

- Designed completely new touch-screen interface designed for efficiency and clarity for use in operating rooms by Anesthesiologists
- Consulted on-site with Anesthesiologists to determine their workflow and application needs

Research Assistant & Developer: University of Iowa

Iowa City, IA

2003-2005

+ Built Rails Application to organize, warehouse and process the huge volume of fMRI research data and metadata collected

# Education

University of Iowa, Bachelor of Science — Computer Science, 2001

# Skills / Favorite Technologies

- Ruby on Rails
- + Ruby itself, 1.8.x-1.9.x
- + Sinatra
- ◆ Javascript, jQuery, jQueryUI
- + HTML5, CSS3
- ◆ MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL (at home with non-trivial SQL queries, dual-key-indices, etc)
- + BDD tools including RSpec, MiniTest, FactoryGirl/Machinist, Capybara, Jasmine
- + iOS/Objective C/Cocoa
- + Far too many gems to list

# Availability

I choose to spend 1-2 days per week with my two children and as such require a schedule of approximately 3 to 3 1/2 working days per week. I typically work about 30 hours per week. I'm unable to relocate away from Madison but have a record of successful remote work. The time spent away from the keyboard means I can truly focus when I am there, I find my productivity is not too far off of what many accomplish in 40 hours.